<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Signal&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://signalyu.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Signal&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>EN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 16:39:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://signalyu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/design-patterns/1-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 14:38:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/design-patterns/1-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>1. Solid Principle 1.1 Single Responsibility Principle A class should have only one reason to change, meaning each class should focus on a single functionality or responsibility.
SHOW CODE Single Responsibility Principle import java.io.IOException; import java.util.*; import java.util.regex.*; import com.fasterxml.jackson.databind.ObjectMapper; /** * 1. User class is only used to represent entity. * 2. UserValidator class is solely responsible for validating user objects. * 3. Store class is only used to manage user objects storage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coding Patterns</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/patterns/1-coding-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 10:15:04 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/patterns/1-coding-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Simple Two Pointers The Simple Two Pointers technique is commonly used to solve problems involving sorted array, where a set of elements needs to be found that satisfy certain constrains. This approach is efficient in scenarios such as finding a pair that sums to a target or reversing an array or string. In the two simple two pointers technique, two pointers &amp;ndash; typically labeled &amp;ldquo;left&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; are initialized and move in a specific direction based on the problem&amp;rsquo;s requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database Design</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/database-design/1-database-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 21:07:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/database-design/1-database-design/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Databases A database is a collection of data that is stored, managed, and accessed electronically. It typically contains one or more tables, which resemble Excel or Google sheets, with data organized into rows and columns. As the number of tables grows, managing the database can become complex, making it essential to design a scalable and maintainable strucutre.
Databases can be broadly categorized into two types: Relational database, primarily used for real-time data updates and transactions, and data warehouse, optimized for data analysis and reporting purposes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Structure &amp; Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/algorithms/1-data-structure-and-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 20:29:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/algorithms/1-data-structure-and-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Recursion Recursion is a programming technique where a function repeatedly calls itself until it reaches a base case, whcih stops the recursion and allows it to return a result. It is a way of breaking down complex problems into smaller, simpler subproblems that are eaiser to solve.
Head Recursion Head Recursion is a type of recursion where a function makes its recursive call first, immediately after checking the base case, and performs all other operations only after the recursive call returns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Junit &amp; Mockito Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/framework/backend/unit-testing/1-junit-and-mockito-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 01:26:33 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/framework/backend/unit-testing/1-junit-and-mockito-notes/</guid>
      <description>JUnit assertEquals In JUnit, assertEquals is a method used to check if the expected value and the actual value are equal in unit tests.
SHOW CODE Java import org.junit.jupiter.api.Test; import static org.junit.jupiter.api.Assertions.assertEquals; public class UnitTest { @Test void addition() { Calculator calculator = new Calculator(); int result = calculator.add(1, 1); assertEquals(2, result, &#34;The result of 1 + 1 should be 2&#34;); } } assertTure &amp;amp; assertFalse In JUnit, the assertTrue and the assertFalse methods are used to validate boolean expressions in unit tests.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asynchronous Messaging</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/asynchronous-messaging/1-asynchronous-messaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 13:57:02 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/asynchronous-messaging/1-asynchronous-messaging/</guid>
      <description>Synchronous Messaging VS. Asynchronous Messaging Synchronous Messaging and Asynchronous Messaging are two commnication paradigms used in distributed systems. In synchronous messaging, the sender will not continue executing until it receives the acknowledged message from the receiver. This paradigm is commonly used in situations that require immediate feedback to continue operations, such as payments or transaction processing.
The advantages of this paradigm include ease of implementation and usefulness in situations where immediate feedback is needed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database Management Systems</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/database-management-system/1-database-management-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 10:20:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/database-management-system/1-database-management-system/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to DBMS A Database Management System (DBMS) is software that provides an interface for users to interact with databases. It enables the management, storage, and manipulation of data within databases. DBMS can be broadly classified into two main types: Relational DBMS and NoSQL DBMS.
In a Relational DBMS, data is stored in structured tables and is manipulated using SQL (Structured Query Language). Examples of relational DBMS inlcude MySQL, Oracle, and PostgreSQL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multithreading &amp; Concurrency</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/multithreading-and-concurrency/1-multithreading-and-concurrency/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 12:13:32 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/multithreading-and-concurrency/1-multithreading-and-concurrency/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Multithreading Program, Process, and Thread A program is a static set of instructions that stores on a disk. A process is an instance of a program that is currently being executed by the operating system. A thread is a small unit of process that can be scheduled and executed by the operating system. In simpler terms, a program is the code, a process is the excution of the code, a thread is a unit of execution within a process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>System Design</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/system-design/1-system-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 04:32:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/system-design/1-system-design/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to System Design System Design is the process of defining the architecture, components, modules, interfaces, and data for a system to fulfill specific business requirements, while ensuring scalability, maintainability, and performance.
Load Balancing In System Design, Load Balancing refers to the practice of distributing incoming network traffic or workload across multiple servers or resources to optimize resource use and ensure high availability.
Load Balancing To fullly leverage scalability and redundency, load balancing can occur at different layers: between user and the web server, between web server and an internal platform serve, between internal platform server and database as illustrated in the following image:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Computer Organization</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/meocs-408/1-principles-of-computer-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 16:39:09 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/meocs-408/1-principles-of-computer-organization/</guid>
      <description>Basic Components of Compiter Hardware Von Neumann Architecture Von Neumann Architecture is a computer architecture model that forms the foundation of modern computer systems. It primarily consists of five major components: the CPU, Memory, Input Devices, Output Devices, and Buses.
The CPU (Central Processing Unit) contains two main parts: the Algorithmic and Logic Unit (ALU) and the Control Unit. The ALU performs mathematical calculations and logical operations, while the Control Unit manages the processor&amp;rsquo;s operations by fetching, decoding, and executing instructions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn English With Speeches</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/2-learn-english-with-speeches/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 09:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/2-learn-english-with-speeches/</guid>
      <description>1. STEVE JOBS: Stanford Speech https://youtu.be/1i9kcBHX2Nw SHOW SUBTITLES I am honored to be with you today at your commencement from one of the finest universities in the world. I never graduated from college. Truth be told, this is the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever gotten to a college graduation. Today I want to tell you three stories from my life. That&amp;rsquo;s it. No big deal. Just three stories.
The first story is about connecting the dots.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coding Problem Set</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/programming/coding-problems/1-cocoding-problem-set/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 15:15:55 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/programming/coding-problems/1-cocoding-problem-set/</guid>
      <description>String 华为OD机试：字符串分割【100分】 点击查看题目 一、题目描述
给定一个非空字符串 S，其中包含多个子串，这些子串由 - 符号分隔。我们还给定一个正整数 K，要求按以下规则转换字符串：
对于字符串中的每个子串，从第二个子串开始，将其分为每 K 个字符的片段。 对每个片段应用以下转换规则： 如果片段中小写字母数量多于大写字母，将该片段的所有大写字母转换为小写字母。 如果片段中大写字母数量多于小写字母，将该片段的所有小写字母转换为大写字母。 如果大写和小写字母数量相等，不做转换。 二、输入描述
输入包含两行：
第一行为整数 K。 第二行为字符串 S，由 - 分隔成多个子串。 三、输出描述
输出转换后的字符串。
四、测试用例
测试用例 1 输入
3 12abc-abcABC-4aB@ 输出
12abc-abc-ABC-4aB-@ 说明
子串为 12abc、abcABC、4aB@。第一个子串保留。 对 abcABC 按每 3 个字符分组为 abc 和 ABC： abc 中小写字母多，转换为 abc。 ABC 中大写字母多，转换为 ABC。 对 4aB@ 按每 3 个字符分组为 4aB 和 @： 4aB 中大小写字母数量相等，不做转换。 @ 中无字母，不做转换。 最终输出为 12abc-abc-ABC-4aB-@。 测试用例 2
输入
3 Test-aaBBcc-CCddEE 输出</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning English With Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/1-learning-english-with-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 08:08:19 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/1-learning-english-with-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>1. Order Food in Restaurant https://youtu.be/_izDbJ45Q5I SHOW NOTES I&#39;m still working on it. This sentence expresses that an action is ongoing and not yet completed. It also suggests that more time is needed to finish it. Did you finish reading? — I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it. Did you fix my car? — I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it. Coke and Fries This refers to a popular combination of fast food: Coca-cola and French Fries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Idea &amp; Maven &amp; Postman Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/tools/1-idea-maven-postman-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 16:03:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/tools/1-idea-maven-postman-notes/</guid>
      <description>IDEA Maven Introduction to Maven Maven is a build automation and project management tool primarily used for Java projects. It follows the concept of Project Object Model (POM), which is defined in an XML file (pom.xml) at the root of the project.
settings.xml Configuration ./ ├── bin/ │ ├── m2.conf │ ├── mvn* │ ├── mvn.cmd │ ├── mvnDebug* │ ├── mvnDebug.cmd │ └── mvnyjp* ├── boot/ │ ├── plexus-classworlds-2.7.0.jar │ └── plexus-classworlds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/framework/backend/spring/1-spring-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 15:44:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework-and-tools/framework/backend/spring/1-spring-notes/</guid>
      <description>Core Concepts Loose Coupling Loose Coupling is a design principle that aims to reduce the dependencies between components within a system.
Inversion of Control (IoC) Inversion of Control is a design principle where the control of object creation and lifecycle management is transferred from the application code to an external container or framework.
Dependency Injection (DI) Dependency Injection is a design pattern commonly used in object-oriented programming, where the dependecies of a class are provided externally rather than being created within the class itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java Programming Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/programming/java/1-java-programming-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 11:36:53 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/programming/java/1-java-programming-notes/</guid>
      <description>Enum In Java, an enum (short for &amp;ldquo;enumeration&amp;rdquo;) is used to define a collection of constants, such as days of the week or months of the year. An enum provides a type-safe way to handle constant values, and it can be used in a switch statement or for comparison using ==. Compared to a final constant in Java, an enum can contain fields, methods, and constructors. The values() method is used to retrive all the constants in an enum, and the valueOf() method is used to convert a string into an enum constant.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
