<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Signal&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Signal&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>EN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:07:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://signalyu.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mottos</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/personal-growth/1-mottos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 21:25:35 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/personal-growth/1-mottos/</guid>
      <description>2024 Be cautious in both speech and action.
First things first.
Avoid living a life of suffering.
Opportunity favors the prepared mind.
Focus on your own matters, respect others&amp;rsquo; choices, and live in harmony with destiny.
Life is the process of cultivating your soul.
Think first, act later.
Speak less of what&amp;rsquo;s unnecessary, do less of what&amp;rsquo;s pointless, and waste less energy on what&amp;rsquo;s unimportant.
In times of peace, prepare for challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Database Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/1-database-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 21:07:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/database/1-database-notes/</guid>
      <description>Database Design Introduction to Databases A database is a collection of data that is stored, managed, and accessed electronically. It typically contains one or more tables, which resemble Excel or Google sheets, with data organized into rows and columns. As the number of tables grows, managing the database can become complex, making it essential to design a scalable and maintainable strucutre.
Databases can be broadly categorized into two types: Relational database, primarily used for real-time data updates and transactions, and data warehouse, optimized for data analysis and reporting purposes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework/backend/spring/1-spring-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 15:44:50 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework/backend/spring/1-spring-notes/</guid>
      <description>Core Concepts Loose Coupling Loose Coupling is a design principle that aims to reduce the dependencies between components within a system.
Inversion of Control (IoC) Inversion of Control is a design principle where the control of object creation and lifecycle management is transferred from the application code to an external container or framework.
Dependency Injection (DI) Dependency Injection is a design pattern commonly used in object-oriented programming, where the dependecies of a class are provided externally rather than being created within the class itself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vue Notes</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework/front-end/vue/1-vue-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 20:53:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/framework/front-end/vue/1-vue-notes/</guid>
      <description>Virtual DOM A Virtual DOM is a lightweight, in-memory representation of the real DOM. Each Node in the Virtual DOM is represented as a plain JavaScript object with properties describing the element, its attributes, and its children. The Virtual DOM will be updated whenever an application&amp;rsquo;s state changes. It minimizes real DOM updates by batching changes and applying them through an optimized process. --- title: Virtual DOM --- graph TD B[&#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Structure &amp; Algorithms</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/1-data-structure-and-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:29:21 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/data-structures-and-algorithms/1-data-structure-and-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>Recursion Recursion is a programming technique where a function repeatedly calls itself until it reaches a base case, whcih stops the recursion and allows it to return a result. It is a way of breaking down complex problems into smaller, simpler subproblems that are eaiser to solve.
Head Recursion Head Recursion is a type of recursion where a function makes its recursive call first, immediately after checking the base case, and performs all other operations only after the recursive call returns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/design-patterns/1-design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 14:38:17 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/4-engineering-and-technology/computer-science/design-patterns/1-design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>1. Solid Principle 1.1 Single Responsibility Principle A class should have only one reason to change, meaning each class should focus on a single functionality or responsibility.
SHOW CODE Single Responsibility Principle import java.io.IOException; import java.util.*; import java.util.regex.*; import com.fasterxml.jackson.databind.ObjectMapper; /** * 1. User class is only used to represent entity. * 2. UserValidator class is solely responsible for validating user objects. * 3. Store class is only used to manage user objects storage.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
