<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Languages on Signal&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://signalyu.github.io/tags/languages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Languages on Signal&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.126.1</generator>
    <language>EN</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:25:36 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://signalyu.github.io/tags/languages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>English Speaking: IELTS (201-300)</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/5-english-speaking-ielts-201-300/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:25:36 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/5-english-speaking-ielts-201-300/</guid>
      <description>201-210 201. Do you think it&amp;rsquo;s better to learn in a coeducational or single sex school? Well, definitely the coed school. Because in a coed environment, students have the opportunity to interact with peers of both genders, it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to develop their social skills. Single-sex schools might provide a more focused learning environment, but life is not just about acquiring book knowledge, is about learning a wide range of things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Speaking: IELTS (101-200)</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/4-english-speaking-ielts-101-200/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 20:33:58 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/4-english-speaking-ielts-101-200/</guid>
      <description>101-110 101. Are people isolating themselves from society these days? Yeah, many people have become addicted to social media, they prefer staying home and interacting online instead of engaging in face-to-face conversations. And the fast-paced modern life also makes people feeling disconnected.
102. What responsibilities do citizens of a nation have? Th first is attending school; in China, everyone is required to complete nine years of compulsory education. The second is, Citizens must obey the law, as following legal regulations helps maintain social stability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning English With Podcasts</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/1-learning-english-with-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 08:08:19 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/listening/english/1-learning-english-with-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>1. Order Food in Restaurant https://youtu.be/_izDbJ45Q5I SHOW NOTES I&#39;m still working on it. This sentence expresses that an action is ongoing and not yet completed. It also suggests that more time is needed to finish it. Did you finish reading? — I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it. Did you fix my car? — I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it. Coke and Fries This refers to a popular combination of fast food: Coca-cola and French Fries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>English Speaking: IELTS (1-100)</title>
      <link>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/2-english-speaking-ielts-1-100/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 09:04:13 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://signalyu.github.io/posts/3-humanities/languages/speaking/english/2-english-speaking-ielts-1-100/</guid>
      <description>1-10 1. Do you work or do you study? I currently working. I finished my studies four years ago. So I&amp;rsquo;m currently working as a software engineer.
2. Where do you currently work? I currently work in Shenzhen. I came in Shenzhen two years ago. I worked previously in Guangzhou where I completed my education.
3. Why did you choose that carrer? Well, actually. I have a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in economics.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
